GULMEE KASHYAP

(+91)-9535315656 gulmeekashyap@gmail.com

A Certified Scrum Product Owner® (CSPO®) with 8 Years of experience & exposure to various stages of SDLC in Software Product; currently working as Product Manager -III. Aspire to work in a collaborative milieu that stimulates creative instincts and handle responsibilities that effectively leverage my leadership skills as well as technical expertise and offer ample opportunity for continuous learning & development whilst driving effective product management from cradle to grave.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Product Manager- III, April 2019 - Present

Tally Solutions Private Limited

Current Responsibilities:

- Spearheading of multiple Discovery projects for future roadmap of the company like- In-product Chat support, Offline VAS & preliminary Mobile App.
- Participate in designing the Induction program for new recruits & mentored 3 management trainees to be production ready.
- Contribute in building a generic framework for Product Acceptance covering aspects like-simplicity, completeness, correctness, usability, ease of training & adoption etc. Conducted multiple product acceptance sessions for multiple areas of the product.
- Finalizing the right product management metrics, customer journey map & promotional videos/digital content for upcoming major release besides playing Product Owner role for installation, startup, data & application management areas and driving their 'inception to market' activities.

Product Manager- II, June 2017 - March 2019

Tally Solutions Private Limited

Responsibilities handled:

- Leveraging my learnings from previous roles, I devised an easy to use template for Specification writing that was widely adopted across different teams as it was quick to start, easy to update/maintain and readily consumable by developers, testers, marketing & support teams. The use of Wireframes & Mock-ups in Specification led to minimal iterations and made the Specifications self-explanatory.
- Handled responsibility of market research, requirement gathering, analysis & creation of requirement specification for technical areas of the product along with backlog grooming. Inclusion of Problem Statements, scope in the document & showing a clear correlation of the same to organization's objective & vision helped in on-boarding stakeholders from R&D, testing, sales, marketing & support teams.
- Conducted several VoC sessions with internal as well as external users for the new product features before major releases. Apart from the direct feedback received, I noted many observations regarding the way people use the product which influenced several crucial design decisions and helped in bringing out an intuitive user experience.
- Actively participated in Customer Centricity program and became the voice of many customers by projecting their requirements & challenges to top management for quick action. This customer advocacy was widely appreciated across the organization.

- Conducted several product walk-throughs, demos & 'train the trainer' events in & outside the
 organization during major product releases. Also contributed in enabling the support function in new
 product features as well as reviewed marketing collaterals, reference manual content and website
 content for major releases.
- Contributed in creation of GTM for various market segments and prepared Market Stories for several areas of the product. Also prepared the product roadmap for 2 areas.
- Pioneered a culture of learning in the team and started an initiative of group learning activities to encourage team for learning product management concepts and apply them in day-to-day work.

Test Manager- R&D, November 2013 - May 2017

Tally Solutions Private Limited

Responsibilities handled:

- Handled a team of 3-10 Test Engineers and carried out responsibilities related to Test Planning/strategy, Resource Estimation/management, Test Lab Management & Requirement handling, Test Reporting & setting up Internal Processes & practices in the team for over 32 major Releases of two products.
- Played the role of Scrum Master for 3 different scrum teams and managed to achieve Best Team award for 2 consecutive quarters.
- Designed a few People Development programs such as- Team Induction Program for quicker onboarding of new hires that enabled them to get involved in product testing within 3 weeks and Team Activity Framework based on 12 essential skills of a tester. Devised easy to use templates for Test Cases, Test results, bug reporting & Test reports which were adopted across teams.
- Initiated building up of Test Case Repository for the product areas from scratch and devised various MS Excel based Tracking mechanisms to facilitate real-time & automated Test result update.
- Acted as a trailblazer for adoption of Exploratory Testing & inclusion of Compatibility testing in the
 final testing cycle. Also mentored the team in leveraging the benefit of tools like Mind maps, Flow
 charts & Matrix to construct effective test cases.

Manager- Delivery Management (R&D), May 2011 – November 2013

Tally Solutions Private Limited

Responsibilities handled:

- Handled the responsibility of Requirement analysis & documentation, participation in design & design validation, User Acceptance Testing, Customer feedback & issue analysis, Documentation & validation of Release, training the trainers on new features, designing of Training material for trainers as well as for new recruits, contributing to the Question Bank for recruitment & internal employee assessments.
- Carried out multiple internal research initiatives on- Antivirus-Firewall, Virtual setups, Operating systems & Data File extensions etc. to aid in decision making for infrastructure procurement and design roadmap.
- Conducted multiple full day Partner Enablement sessions during Major product Releases that involved product walk-throughs and hands on workshops in addition to designing & conducting Induction product trainings for new hires.
- As Project Manager for the initiative on Pre-Release testing of Windows 8 and Windows 10, ensured timely completion of project for 3 products in coordination with Microsoft.

EDUCATION

- **PGDM** in *Telecom Management (SYSTEMS)* from MIT School of Telecom Management Pune, Maharashtra in the year 2011.
- **B.E.** in *Electronics & Telecommunication* from North Maharashtra University, Jalgaon, in the year 2009.

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- Certified Scrum Product Owner® (CSPO®)
- Conceptual knowledge of ERP, SDLC, Agile, Product Management.
- Go to person in the team for presentations, articulation & ideas
- Strong Planning & Organizing, Analytical, Communication and Documentation skills.
- Good observer, active listener & passionate about chasing quality
- Tools:
 - MS Office tools (MS Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Visio)
 - Test Management tools (Test Link, QA Complete, SpiraTest) & Testing tools (Postman, JMeter, SmartSniff, NetBalancer, WANem)
 - Bug Tracking & Project Management tool (JIRA)
 - Other tools (Atlassian Confluence, SharePoint, Jenkins, Xmind, Aha)

AWARDS/RECOGNITIONS

- Winner of **Impact Player of the Release** Award for 2018-19
- 3 times Winner of **Star of the Quarter** Award in 2017-19
- Winner of **Pat on the back** Award in 2016-17